Guide to the Tompkins County Health Association records, 1915-1968.
Tompkins County Health Association records, 1915-1968
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Tompkins County Health Association records, 1915-1968.
2921
Tompkins County Health Association.
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, histories, newsletters, pamphlets, minutes, notebooks, annual reports, programs, personnel records, photographs, scrapbooks, and newspaper articles.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, reports, histories of local health associations, newsletters, pamphlets, minutes, notebooks, annual reports, programs, personnel records, photographs, scrapbooks, and newspaper articles.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, reports, histories of local health associations, newsletters, pamphlets, minutes, notebooks, annual reports, programs, personnel records, photographs, scrapbooks, and newspaper articles.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Tompkins County Health Association.
Subjects:
Health.; Public health--New York (State)--Tompkins County.
Places:
Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Politics and government.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Histories
  - Notes on Origin and History of the Ithaca Tuberculosis Association - correspondence, reports - 1917-1925, 1936-1937, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Correspondents: Livingston Farrand, Mrs. V.D. Morse, Mrs. E.H. Zellar, R.D. Fear, Dr. Luzerne Coville, F.D. Boynton; Ithaca Tuberculosis Association, Ithaca Public Schools Board of Education, Department of Health, State of N.Y.
  - History of the Tompkins County Health Association - history, resume, report, correspondence, agenda for meetings, lists of members, biography - 1942-1947, 1949, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Correspondents: Paul Gerhardt, Herman Biggs, J. Nelbach; American Cancer Society
  - Voluntary Health Agencies - History & Accomplishments - pamphlets, reports, speech, memo - 1950-1955, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Correspondent: A.W. Osborn
  - History of Tuberculosis - newsletter, pamphlets, history - 1945-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondents: Henry Brooks Parker; NYS Department of Health
- Minutes
  - Ithaca Tuberculosis Association - minutes book - 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Tompkins County Tuberculosis and Public Health Association - minutes, correspondence - 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes - 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alphabetical files
  - Annual Reports - programs, pamphlets, reports - 1938-1962, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Correspondents: Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association, Cancer Society
  - Association Letter Kit - report, directory, minute - 1941-1942, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Correspondent: American Heart Association
  - Biggs Hospital Service Committee - minutes of meeting, annual report, ms. letters - 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bulletins - bulletins, correspondence, ms. report, pamphlets, minutes, volume unbound - 1942-1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Christmas Seal Sale, 1945-1946 - citation, correspondence, printed, sample letters - 1943-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - correspondence, ms. letters, telegram, personnel records, information blank - 1946-1952, 1954-1957, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Correspondents: Dr. H.H. Crum, Prof. S.W. Landon, John L. Wallace, Mr. G.L. Welbach, Clayton Weber; State Committee on Tuberculosis & Public Health, Rochester Chamber of Commerce, Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association
  - Friendship Committee - Minutes - correspondence, mss. letters, minutes of meeting - 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Correspondent: Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association
  - Hospital Service Committee - Minutes - report, pamphlet, letter, minutes, mss. notes - 1951, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Correspondents: R.W. Osborn; Health Association of Tompkins County
  - Loan Closet - Mr. Rice - report, pamphlet, loan closet lists - 1960-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Nominating Committee 1961, Mrs. Kelly - mss notes, correspondence, lists of members, Ithaca Journal articles - 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Correspondents: Mrs. Kelly; Health Association of Tompkins County
  - Photographs - 1937-1938, 1953-1962, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Scrapbooks
  - Newspaper articles - 1920-1934 (Box 2, Volume 1)
  - Newspaper articles - 1931-1940 (Box 2, Volume 2)
  - Scrapbook of Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association - newspaper articles - 1941-1943 (Box 2, Volume 3)
  - Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association, 101 N. Cayuga Street, Ithaca, N.Y. 14850 - newspaper articles - 1943-1946 (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - Hospital Service Committee of Biggs Memorial Hospital - photos, minutes, reports, pamphlets, typed letters - 1944-1948 (Box 2, Volume 5)
  - Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association - newspaper articles - 1946-1949 (Box 2, Volume 6)
  - Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association - correspondence, pamphlets, minutes, photos, newspaper articles - 1946-1950 (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Association - paper, newspaper articles - 1950 (Box 4, Volume 2)
    Previously Vol. 3 in Box 3. Date was corrected.
  - Newspaper articles, pamphlets, photos - 1950-1951 (Box 3, Volume 3)
    Previously Vol. 2 in Box 3.
  - Tompkins County Tuberculosis & Public Health Assn., Inc. - newspaper articles - 1952-1953 (Box 3, Volume 4)
  - Newspaper articles - 1951-1959 (Box 3, Volume 5)
  - Christmas Seal Sale, 1952 - newpaper articles - 1952-1956 (Box 3, Volume 6)
  - Newspaper articles - 1956 (Box 3, Volume 7)
  - Newspaper articles, photo - 1956-1958 (Box 3, Volume 8)
  - Heart clippings - newspaper articles - 1958-1960 (Box 3, Volume 9)
  - Christmas Seals & Tuberculosis - newspaper articles - 1958-1960 (Box 3, Volume 10)
  - Health Clippings - newspaper articles - 1960 (Box 3, Volume 11)